# **George Salteris**

www.linkedin.com/in/georgesalteris

#### **Summary**

Software engineer with three years of experience in coding and testing, seeking a job as a data scientist. Strong hands-on experience of Java, Python, PHP, SQL, and object-oriented development. An enthusiastic team player and creative thinker. Enjoy investigating "chaotic" large-scale datasets and exporting important business information by gaining full insight into the underlying trends. Excellent skills in high-level programming and aptitude for adaptation to new programming languages.

#### Education

#### W. P. Carey School of Business at Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

May 2019

Master of Science in Business Analytics (MSBA)

Project: "Measuring engagement of the Notebowl social learning platform for white paper results"

Dataset Type: User engagement on the learning platform along with their score. Size: 700,000 rows.

Techniques: Employed regression techniques using Python to predict if the user engagement correlated with user's grades.

Outcome: work in progress.

## Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering at University of Ioannina, Ioannina, Greece

July 2018

Master of Science in Computer Science & Engineering

Thesis: "Phenotype Prediction Using Genotype Information"

Dataset Type: Genomic data with 0.07% having Cancer Melanoma. Size: 272,176 patients, out of 11tb genomic dataset.

Techniques: Employed a five-step pipeline for data transformation, then applied logistic regression and SVM techniques using Python.

Outcome: Achieved 89% accuracy and 73% recall on cancer prediction based on certain genomic features.

## Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering at University of Ioannina, Ioannina, Greece

July 2018

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Engineering

#### **Professional Qualifications**

- Machine Learning Techniques
- Data Manipulation & Visualization
- Data Management

- Decision Analysis
- Analysis, Design and Implementation of Databases
- Software: R, Python, SQL, Java, JavaScript, PHP, Ionic, HTML, CSS, Spark.
- AngularJs, D3.js, Laravel, Tableau, VueJs.

#### **Professional Experience**

#### **Software Engineer**

Dec 2017 - Aug 2018

Hellenic Army, Athens, Greece

- Developed the entire application stack using Laravel, SQL, HTML 5, Javascript and VueJS for two applications for the Greek Army.
- Designed and created MySQL Database for a web and mobile application to assist military personnel in finding available housing.
- Leveraged RESTful APIs to integrate the database and backend components with the mobile application including adhering to ISO 27001.

## Software Engineer-Team Manager

Dec 2017 – Jan 2019

VNimbus P.C, Athens, Greece

- Led a team of three engineers tasked with developing a platform for event management and reservations using Laravel, HTML 5 and VueJS.
- Designed and deployed websites using Laravel and HTML 5, for several industries including construction, hospitality and psychometrics.

## Junior Software Engineer

Oct 2016 - Nov 2017

Tooristas.com, Athens, Greece

- Designed front end administration (content management) and business panel using Angular JS for event management businesses.
- Assisted in backend issues and developed several APIs to update the MySQL database.

#### **Software Engineer Intern**

July 2016 - Sep 2016

SingularLogic, Athens, Greece

Assisted in backend issues and developed several APIs to update the MySQL database.

## **Professional Development**

Aug 2018 - present

## **Director of Engagement**

#### W. P. Carey School of Business at Arizona State University

- Selected to be part of the leadership board of MSBA program.
- Organized several events to enhance communication among students.
- Raised several concerns to program administration and proposed ideas to improve the program.